本讲座为您提供了一些先进的图像处理操作，但是
This lecture's given you a flavour of some advanced image processing operations, but
真的只是触及了一些这些技术。所以，如果他们引起了你的兴趣，
really only just touched on some of these techniques. So if they've piqued your interest,
然后我建议你去做一些额外的阅读并试验一些代码
then I suggest you go off and do some additional reading and experiment with some of the code
这是在工具箱中提供的。
that's provided in the toolbox.
我们看到的第一种技术是数学形态学，但这一次是
The first technique that we looked at was mathematical morphology, but this time with
更复杂的结构元素。所以我们谈到了如何使用形态学操作
more complex structuring elements. So we talked about how we can use morphological operations
检测图像中具有特定斜率的线。实际上，我们可以创建相当复杂
to detect lines with a particular slope within an image. We can actually create quite complex
结构元素。
structuring elements.
我们还讨论了一个结构元素包含一个圆圈的例子，我们使用了它
We also discussed an example where the structuring element contained a circle and we used that
重建一个对象的一些缺失部分;番茄果实，我们知道它本质上是
to reconstruct some missing parts of an object; a tomato fruit, which we know is essentially
圆。
circular.
我们简要地看了一下命中和未命中变换。我们可以将它用于操作
We looked very briefly at the hit and miss transform. We can use that for operations
比较骨架化并找到许多线段的交点。
like skeletonization and finding the intersection points of a number of line segments.
我们介绍了Hough变换，这是一种众所周知的寻找线性特征的技术
We introduced the Hough Transform, a well-known technique of finding linear features within
一个图像。为了使用Hough变换，我们引入了替代参数化
an image. In order to use the Hough Transform, we introduced an alternative parameterization
的线条。
of lines.
它通常不被称为线的极地形式。每条线都用。来描述
It's not often known as the Polar Form of a Line. Each line is described in terms of
周边的Theta和Rho。位于图像边缘的每个点都投票给一个大的
the perimeter Theta and Rho. Each point that lays on an edge of an image, votes for a large
行数。这些投票在累加器数组中计算。收到的行
number of lines. Those votes are tallied in an accumulator array. The lines that receive
然后，最多的票数是场景中的主导线;他们得到了支持
the largest number of votes then are dominant lines in the scene; they are supported by
大量的边缘像素和这样的线已经在图像上以图形方式重叠
a large number of edge pixels and such lines have been overlaid graphically on the image
在这里的教堂。
of the church here.
最后，我们讨论了找到相应的观点。你和我很容易找到
Finally we talked about finding corresponding points. It's very easy for you and me to find
这个阳台角落的坐标在两张截然不同的照片中
the coordinate of this balcony corner in two quite different pictures of that same
场景，但计算机算法并不那么容易。
scene, but it's not so easy for a computer algorithm to do that.
我们还谈到了我们不能仅仅依赖于灰度强度的问题
We also touched on the problem that we can't just rely on the grey scale intensity of the
像素在另一个场景中找到它。
pixel to find it in the other scene.
为了解决这个问题，我们引入了角点检测器的概念，它说
In order to solve this problem we introduced the notion of a Corner Detector, which says
关于图像区域与图像的相邻区域的相似性的事物。
something about the similarity of a region of an image, to adjacent regions of the image.
我们可以将其归结为一个非常有用的二乘二矩阵，称为结构张量。
We can boil this down to a very useful two by two matrix called the Structure Tensor.
这告诉我们很多关于图像强度表面的局部形状
And that tells us a lot about the local shape of the intensity surface of the image at this
特别的一点。我们可以使用该矩阵的特征值来确定该区域是否存在
particular point. We can use the Eigenvalues of this matrix to determine whether this region
图像是平坦的还是恒定的，无论它是否包含边缘或是否包含
of the image is flat or constant, whether it contains and edge or whether it contains
一个顶峰。
a peak.
从水平和垂直梯度非常容易地计算结构张量
The structure tensor is very easily computed from the horizontal and vertical gradient
用高斯内核平滑的图像。这些都是我们之前遇到过的技术。
images smoothed with a Gaussian Kernel. These are all techniques that we've met previously.
两种常见的角点检测器算法然后使用稍微不同的技术来查找
Two common corner detector algorithms then use slightly different techniques to find
两个特征值都很大的那些点。
those points where both Eigenvalues are large.
最后，我们讨论了功能匹配。鉴于我有一组角点
Finally, we talked about feature matching. Given that I had a set of corner points in
一个图像，另一个图像中的一组角点，我在每个图像周围采用一个像素区域
one image, a set of corner points in another image, I take a region of pixels around each
在那些兴趣点中，并查看那些图像区域的相似性以确定对应关系
of those interest points and look at the similarity of those image regions to determine the correspondence
在两个图像中的点之间。
between points in the two images.